Okay so now that we have our button off.
We have our needle threaded.
Now I'm going to show you how to sew this button on.
And we can see the holes from where it was before.
And another thing that we want to do before we even get started, you'll look at the other buttons.
And I can see that the thread is going vertical on this, on these buttons, not horizontal sideways.
So I want to make sure that I sew this button on with the holes top to bottom.
Okay so what we want to do is find the holes where they were before.
And just, I'm going to run the needle through the bottom hole and I'm just going to pinch a little piece and come out through the top.
Just like that.
And just pull it.
And you know what?
If you yanked it really hard I bet it would just come right out.
Oh no it doesn't.
Sometimes it'll do that.
You just yank it.
See like that?
It'll come out?
And that's okay.
That's no big deal.
That just means you need to maybe grab a little bit below that hole and come out through the top hole.
So just kind of bypass one hole.
And now it won't come out.
It's stuck in there really good.
So we don't want the knot on the back.
We just want it on the front.
Just pinch a little piece.
And now we're ready to put the thread through the first hole of the button.
Hold it still like this and just put it through one side.
You can run it all the way through and a lot of people make the mistake of forgetting to put it through the second hole and going straight for the fabric.
Don't do that.
What you want to do is put it through the second hole.
And there it is.
And I'm just going to hold the button and just gently slide it down the thread to where it's fitting right there and then I'm going to go look where I have the knot and just go right below the knot and stick it through to the other side.
Just do one side at a time.
Now we don't have to do any more catching the front and the back.
So if you look at the back you have the first initial loop.
You just want to put your needle right where the top loop is.
Where it goes in and it comes right out the top hole.
And if it does that, that's okay.
You just pull it down.
There you go.
And now we're going to do this again.
And I like to put it in then turn it over and look at the back side at the same time.
So I can make sure that it comes out right where the thread is.
And if you don't get the threads right on top of each other it's okay.
It doesn't make a difference.
It's going to look good no matter what.
And then again you put it right on top where the thread goes in on top, out the top.
We're almost finished.
I like to do maybe three or four runs through it before I tie it off.
There we go.
And you can look and see if it looks the same width.
I think I'm going to do one more.
To get the same amount of thread on this button as the other button.
We want it to look uniform.
Here we go.
And I think that's just going to be perfect.
So now what I'm going to do, I want to turn it over and I'm going to tie a knot on the back.
And it's the same type of knot that you tied when you tied off the needle and thread.
So what I'm going to do is hold this, hold the thread that's coming from the button.
Get the needle, just wrap it around.
And you just hold onto this.
And you can pull the thread that has the needle and just keep pulling it and pulling it.
Put your thumb right on top at this point and just keep pulling it and the knot just lowers itself right around the back of the button.
So I've got one knot and I want to put another one.
I like to make sure that that button's going to stay on there.
So you pull, put your thumb on top, pull away. And now I'm going to clip the thread. I'm just going to clip it maybe like a fourth of an inch from the knot.
There we go.
And now we that button sewn on.
And I'm going to put it through the button hole just to make sure everything is lining up and looks right.
Okay.
There we go.
That's simple as that.
And that's how you sew on a button that has two holes.
And next I'm going to show you how to sew on a button that has four holes.